Guide to the Cased Image File 1840-ongoing PR 12
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Tintype, 3
  - Arthur Towne (Item 3-126)
    Young male figure, front view, wearing white shirt and light necktie, as well as dark jacket, clean-shaven with hair parted on side.
    verso states sitter's name and "Of East New York".
  - Unidentified Male Eames Family Member or Friend [Jacobs, Alfred W.] (Item 3-127)
    Male figure, front view, clean-shaven, white shirt, bow tie, right hand on chest holding jacket.
    verso: "The Original French Pearl Pictures taken at Alfred W. Jacob's Galleries."
  - John J. King [Rodgers & Henderson's Photograph Gallery] (Item 3-128)
    Male figure, front view, half-length, wearing moustache, white shirt, black bow tie, vest, dark coat.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 3-129)
    Male figure, looking off to left of camera, wearing black coat with gray vest, white shirt and small bow-tie, light moustache.
    Another image of the same sitter in "Lucille" container of Cased Images File.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-130)
    Female figure, profile view, wearing black dress with buttons down front and what appear to be bead lining, brooch at collar, earrings, hair parted in middle and styled up.
  - Unidentified Young Male Harper Family Member or Friend (Item 3-131)
    Young boy seated with his hands on armrest, wearing dark jacket and hair parted on side, 1/4 profile, white neckerchief.
  - Unidentified Young Female (Item 3-132)
    Young girl seated wearing plaid shirt and coat with white shirt, hair parted in middle with curls to shoulders and bow on top, hands joined on lap, front view, 3/4 length.
  - 2 Unidentified Young Male Relyea Family Members or Friends, 1883/10/00 (Item 3-133)
    Young Male seated on left wearing black jacket, vest and white collar, handkerchief in pocket, cigarette in mouth, young male standing adjacent with cigarette in mouth wearing dark jacket and pants, full length, white collar, his right arm resting on shou
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-134)
    Female figure, profile view, wearing white collar, brooch, dark dress with buttons down front, earrings, hair parted in middle and pulled back with curl hanging down (long hair).
  - Belle Varker (Item 3-135)
    Female figure, front view, seated, wearing flowered hat, fur trimmed coat, hands gloved and clasped on lap.
  - Unidentified Female [Smith, C.A.N., Mrs.] (Item 3-136)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile view, 3/4-length, wearing large hat with feathers (?) on top, dark dress with buttons down front, gloves, white collar and bow at neck.
  - Unidentified Female [Smith, C.A.N., Mrs.] (Item 3-137)
    Female figure standing beside urn, 3/4-length, wearing white hair piece, black dress with buttons down front, black gloves, tree backdrop.
  - 2 Unidentified Females (Item 3-138)
    Two female figures, one seated and one standing, both wearing black dresses and tall black hats, standing female wearing earrings and facing 3/4 profile.
  - Hattie MacClaren's Doll "Pinkie", ca 1870/00/00 (Item 3-138)
    Large female doll with porcelain head, long curls, wearing polka dotted long sleeved dress, sitting in chair covered with paisley material, hands on lap.
  - Franics P. Harper, 1876/00/00 (Item 3-139)
    Male figure, 1/4 profile, wearing patterned tie with white shirt and black jacket, hair parted on side, sideburns, moustache.
  - Franics P. Harper, 1876/00/00 (Item 3-140)
  - 2 Unidentified Young Females and Unidentified Young Male (Group Portrait) (Item 3-141)
    L-R: seated young boy wearing short pant, stockings, boot, white neckerchief, leaning back in chair; standing young girl with her right arm around boy, wearing black dress with white collar, white bow in hair; seated young girl with her right leg under he
    Accompanying envelope addressed to Margaret Layton of New York.
  - Gen. Winfield Scott (Item 3-142)
    Male figure, 1/4 profile, wearing general's uniform with high white collar, tassels on shoulders, buttons down front of coat in two rows.
  - Unidentified Female [Gennert Bros.] (Item 3-143)
    Female figure seated with hands on lap, wearing dark dress with white cuffs and collar, black snood in hair.
  - Unidentified Male Webb Family Member or Friend (Item 3-144)
    Male figure wearing cap and bow tie, white shirt, dark coat and vest.
  - Unidentified Female Webb Family Member or Friend (Item 3-145)
    Female figure wearing braids and black hairnet, hair parted in middle, dark patterned dress with bow at neck, white collar.
  - Mrs. Nettie Alexander McCook (Item 3-146)
    Young female figure, front view, looking to left of camera, wearing small hat with band around head, brooch-type necklace, seated with her right arm resting on tasseled armrest, wearing black dress.
    Sitter is wife of J.J. McCook.
  - Mrs. W.H. Paine (?) (Item 3-147)
    Female figure, profile view, wearing light colored dress with embroidered pattern down front, hair in corkscrew curls and long to shoulders, earrings, white collar.
    Lock of hair verso of image. Note verso of image is partially legible and states that sitter (Kittie?) was married on August 7th, 1865 to W.H. Paine, Brigadier ADC, Army of the Potomac.
  - Mary Elizabeth Lewis Newton (Item 3-148)
    Female figure, front view, hair parted in middle, wearing white collar, bow tie, earring, hair over ears.
    Handwritten Sitter is F.M. Newton's mother.
  - Sue Ellis (Mrs. John Hewston Jr.) (Item 3-149)
    Profile portrait of female, wearing flowered bonnet with long sash and curls.
  - Mrs. Charles Morris Cox (Ella Volina Palmer), ca 1870/00/00 (Item 3-150)
    Female figure, front view, hair parted in middle, pierced earring visible on left ear, white collar, buttons on dress placed from midriff up to shoulder on left, then to right to neck.
  - Julius Livingston Ellis, 1859/00/00 (Item 3-151)
    Male figure, seated, front view, right hand holding cane with arm resting on chair back, white shirt and bow tie, left hand on lap.
  - Peter Cooper (Item 3-152)
    3/4-length profile of seated male figure wearing eyeglasses, beard under chin and long sideburns.
  - Augustus Van Horne Stuyvesant Sr. (Item 3-153)
    Male figure turned slightly to his right, moustache, blue bow at neck, dark jacket and white collar.
  - Mr. James P. Harper Sr., Mrs. James P. Harper Sr., James P. Harper Jr., Lathrop C. Harper and Unidentified Female (Maid), 1868/09/03 (Item 3-154)
    Male figure standing left wearing black suit, holding top hat, wearing white beard and hair, young boy seated adjacent wearing white blouse and shorts, boots, white stockings, light colored hat; female standing behind wearing white overdress and dark slee
    Duplicates of same image.
  - Violet Miller (Item 3-155)
    African American female figure, front view, wearing white collar, brooch at neck and dark dress.
    Sitter was servant of Palmer Family, affectionately called "Babbie" by the family.
  - Anna Weidenman (Item 3-156)
    Young girl, front view, seated in high chair, short sleeved white gown, left hand holding arm of chair.
    Sitter is daughter of Joseph Weidenman (1829-1893), a landscape architect, and his wife Anna Marguerite Weidenman; Donor is sister of sitter.
  - Mrs. Augustus Van Horne Stuyvesant Sr. (Item 3-157)
    Female figure wearing light colored blouse, white collar, circular brooch, earrings, hair pulled back and parted in middle.
  - Mrs. W.M. Durham and Irene Durham (Item 3-158)
    Female figure seated wearing black dress with white collar, earrings, young girl seated on her lap wearing light colored boots, dark dress with white stripes and ruffles, hair parted on side, female holding handkerchief in her right hand with her arms hol
  - Unidentified Male (Item 3-159)
    Male figure, front view, looking to left of camera, long beard and black coat, black hat, moustache, sideburns.
  - Unidentified Young Female Harper Family Member or Friend (Item 3-160)
    Young girl seated holding shovel, bucket in sand beside her, ocean and rocks backdrop, girl wears white dress and black boots, white hat with ties in bow at neck, 1/4 profile, full length.
  - Unidentified Young Male [Young, J.H.], [1850's-1860's] (Item 3-161)
    Young boy standing, front view, 3/4 length, his right hand resting on back of elaborately carved chair, wearing white shirt and black bow-tie, black jacket buttoned only at top, light colored pants, hair parted on side.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 3-162)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket and dark vest with white shirt, bow tie, white collar, hair in curl above forehead, eyes wide open, 1/4 length.
  - Mary Stagg (Mrs. Wm. Dann) (Item 3-163)
    Female figure seated, 3/4 turn to sitter's right, hair parted in middle and short to above shoulder, wearing patterned dress, bow tie, earrings.
  - Clarina Bartow Shumway (Mrs. Charles Stedman Hanks) (Item 3-164)
    Infant seated, front view, wearing white gown, bracelet on left wrist, ring.
  - Christiana Arcularius or Unidentified Female Harper Family Member or Friend [Rees & Co.] (Item 3-165)
    Infant in long white baby gown, front view, full length, right hand of unidentified person wearing ring off to infant's right holding infant's arm.
  - A. C(?). (Relyea Family Member or Friend) (Item 3-166)
    Young female seated wearing black dress with white collar, brooch, shawl, hair parted in middle, front view.
    Verso inscribed with sitter's name and "11 Years".
  - Unidentified Young Female (Item 3-167)
    Young girl standing wearing patterned dress with necklace, hair parted in middle and short to above neck, her left elbow resting on arm of chair and left hand on stomach.
  - Unidentified Female Stagg Family Member or Friend (Item 3-168)
    Female figure (bust) wearing earrings and dark blouse with black and white bow at neck, hair pulled back and parted in middle.
  - Cornelia White (Item 3-169)
    Female figure seated wearing bonnet, black bow at neck, black dress.
  - Cornelia White or Unidentified Young Female Stuyvesant Family Member or Friend (Item 3-170)
    Female figure wearing light colored blouse, hair pulled back and parted in middle.
  - Unidentified Female White Family Member, ca1867/00/00 (?) (Item 3-171)
    Female figure wearing white blouse, earrings, hair pulled back and parted in middle.
    Accompanying note is mostly illegible, with an ad for Dail Journal 1867 verso.
  - Unidentified Female Brinkerhoff-McNulty Family Member or Friend (Item 3-172)
    Female figure (bust) with floral piece in hair, white blouse and white earrings.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-173)
    Female figure, front view, wearing striped blouse (vertical), hair parted in middle, neckerchief, silhouette.
  - Herman von Drehle, 1876/00/00 ca. (Item 3-174)
    Male figure seated, front view, 3/4 length, with his right arm resting on table with paisley cloth covering, wearing black coat with dark pants, white shirt, black bow-tie, clean shaven.
    HvD inscribed on emulsion.
  - Unidentified Male, 1858/08/09 (Item 3-175)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket, handkerchief in pocket, black bow-tie, white shirt, bearded, 1/4 length.
  - Hattie MacLaren (Item 3-176)
    Young girl standing with right hand gripping back of chair, wearing white dress with plaid sash and bows on sleeves, white hat, full length, white cloth on chair.
  - Hattie MacLaren and Donald Sloane (Item 3-177)
    Two children standing, child on right wearing white dress with plaid sash, hairpiece, child on left wearing all white dress with black boots.
  - Unidentified Female and Unidentified Young Female (Item 3-178)
    Two female figures, female on left seated wearing black bonnet with striped ties, light colored shawl, small purse on lap, patterned skirt (matching patterned skirt on other female, female figure on right wearing black coat with long patterned scarf, bonn
  - 15 Unidentified Males (Group Portrait) (Item 3-179)
    15 Male figures, outdoor scene in front of wood house, back row: 7 Males standing, one wears checked shirt and suspenders, 2 have moustaches and beards, most wearing light colored shirts, one wearing black vest; middle row: 7 seated males, 2 wear hats, on
  - Hannah Caldwell (Smith) Rogers [Oldmsted's Photograph and Gem Gallery] (Item 3-180)
    Female figure, front view, wearing white bonnet, seated.
  - J.S. Warwick (Item 3-181)
    Female figure, profile view, wearing white collar and light colored dress, hair short and light colored, brooch.
  - Louisa Fisher (Hoole) Wyman (Item 3-182)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile, seated and leaning on her left arm, wearing checked dress with white lace cuffs and collar, brooch, white hat, chain on dress.
    Sitter is grandmother of Margaret Louise Wallace.
  - Louisa Fisher (Hoole) Wyman (Item 3-183)
    Female figure, seated, profile view, wearing checked dress with black lace shawl, leaning on her left arm, wearing white hat, white cuffs, hair in bun at back of head.
  - 2 Unidentified Female Kellogg-Comstock Family Members or Friends (Item 3-184)
    Two seated female figures, female on left wearing dark dress with white bow at neck, hair in braided bun on top of head, wearing earrings and brooch, holding purse (?) on lap, female on left wearing decorated hat with large earrings, dark dress with ruffl
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-185)
    Female figure, full length, wearing dark dress with white polka-dots and lace edging, belt, bangs, forest scene with tree and plants, leaning against wooden fence, holding umbrella or material in her left hand.
    Cased Images File contains two other images of this sitter.
  - George Relyea, 1879/08/19 (Item 3-186)
    Young boy seated wearing white gown, ankles crossed, hair parted on side, hands on lap, front view, looking off to left of camera, flowers in background, large chair with tassels on back.
    Inscribed verso with sitter's identification.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-187)
    Female figure, seated, front view, wearing black blouse with white collar and brooch, striped or plaid skirt, hair covering with bow on top, hair parted in middle, bracelets, hands joined on lap.
  - H.E. Sanford (Item 3-188)
    Male figure in uniform with cap and coat buttoned to top, arms at sides, beard and moustache, head slightly tilted.
  - Benjamin P. Brigden (Item 3-189)
    Male (bust), clean-shaven, front view, in striped bow tie and white shirt.
  - Francis Brigden and Mary Carpenter, 1850/00/00-ca1855/00/00 (Item 3-190)
    Two female figures, standing is Brigden, seated is Carpenter, wearing similar white dresses and dark coats, as well as hats and gloves.
    Note at rear of frame identifies sitter and enclosed note from donor identifies date.
  - Unidentified Young Female Brinkerhoff-McNulty Family Member or Friend (Item 3-191)
    Little girl, full length, standing next to chair with right hand resting on side of chair, wearing long curls, long coat, and flat hat.
  - Horace E. Dudley [Holmes, Booth and Hayden] (Item 3-192)
    Male figure, front view, half length with moustache, wearing uniform of civil war soldier with cap and belt, and holding hands clasped on lap.
  - Harrison Turner (Item 3-193)
    Male figure in soldier's uniform with cape, hat, large belt buckle, coat, gun on belt, goatee and moustache, looking off to right of camera, seated with one finger on gun, and other hand on thigh.
    Sitter is identified on accompanying note as member of "5th Mass. Regt - Civil War - went out with Medford Co.".
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-194)
    Female figure seated holding suitcase and fur muff, wearing bonnet with long white ties in bow at neck, fur shawl, black dress, gloves.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 3-195)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket and vest, white shirt and bow-tie, hair parted on side, moustache?.
  - Mrs. Augustus Van Horne Stuyvesant Sr. (Item 3-196)
    Young girl seated facing 3/4 to her left, hair pulled back in bun, wearing white lace collar, small brooch, dark blouse, earrings.
  - 3 Unidentified Males [Smith, C.A.N., Mrs.] (Item 3-197)
    Three male figures, L-R: Seated male wearing derby hat and black coat with velvet collar, hands on lap, wearing black vest, white collar, moustache; Standing male in center wearing bow tie, black coat, black vest, derby hat, moustache, white shirt, his le
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-198)
    Female figure, back towards camera, wearing paisley shawl, hair in long tight curls.
  - Horace E. Dudley (Item 3-199)
    Male figure, front view, hair parted on side, half length, with large moustache, white shirt and collar, and dark coat wearing round glasses.
  - George Relyea, 1878/03/01 (Item 3-200)
    Infant wearing white gown and socks, seated front view, full length.
  - George Relyea, 1879/08/19 (Item 3-201)
    Young boy seated wearing white gown, legs on chair, black boots, hair parted on side, front view, looking off to left of camera, flowers in background.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-202)
    Female figure seated profile, wearing black dress with white collar, knotted neckerchief, bonnet with black tie at neck, scarf on hat, her left arm resting on table.
  - Unidentified Male Webb Family Members or Friends with Instruments (Item 3-203)
    Two male figures standing wearing band uniforms, one holds a baton? And the other a drum, male with baton has long white beard, male with drum is younger and has hair parted on side, tree and water backdrop, both have long dark coats and sashes with large
  - Julia Ann Terpeny, ca. 1875/00/00 (Item 3-204)
    Female figure, front view, looking off to her left, seated with arms folded over armrest, wearing dark dress with white cuffs and white ruffles at collar, earrings, hair in bun on top of head.
  - 2 Unidentified Young Female Carney Family Members or Friends (Item 3-205)
    Two young girls leaning on railing, both wearing hats, one wearing light colored hat and dress, the other wearing dark hat and dress with striped trim, shore backdrop.
  - Adeline Dixon (Item 3-206)
    Elderly woman wearing black suit and earrings, sitting in Adirondack wooden chair/bench against painted backdrop.
  - Belle Roosevelt Hoyt, 1876/00/00 (Item 3-207)
    Female figure, front view, wearing white lace scarf at collar, black dress, earrings, tall black hat, seated, front view.
  - 2 Unidentified Female Relyea Family Members or Friends, Unidentified Young Male Relyea Family Member or Friend and Unidentified Infant Relyea Family Member or Friend (Group Portrait) (Item 3-208)
    L-R: Seated female figure holding infant on lap, wearing striped dress with tall hat, infant wearing white gown, seated young boy wearing black tights, shorts, white blouse with bow-tie, boots, ankles crossed, left arm resting on female to his left, hat o
  - Mrs. R. H. Johnson (Item 3-209)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile view, wearing black coat with white collar, large black highly decorated hat.
    Inscribed verso.
  - Unidentified Young Relyea Family Member or Friend, 1889/01/00 (Item 3-210)
    Young girl seated on table wearing plaid dress with dark collar, hair in curls and short to just below earrings, hands on waist, full length.
    Verso inscription states that sitter is 2 years and 2 months old at time of photo.
  - Horace E. Dudley (Item 3-211)
    Male figure, front view, full length, standing in gateway with left elbow on gate, with large moustache, white shirt, and pocket chain.
    duplicate image
  - Horace E. Dudley (Item 3-212)
  - Hattie MacLaren and Unidentified Female MacLaren Family Member or Friend (Item 3-213)
    Two female figures, adult seated holding right hand of young girl standing in front, girl wearing white dress with striped sash, ribbon in hair, adult in black dress with snood, tassels on armrest between sitters, girl leaning back against table or stand
  - 2 Unidentified Females and 2 Unidentified Young Females (Item 3-214)
    Female figure seated far left wearing white dress and holding what appears to be a cane across her lap, wearing hat with white band and fingerless black gloves, young girl standing wearing white gown, bangs in hair, young girl seated wearing white gown an
    Accompanying note states that the "seated woman worked for Louis and Martha Rupp - 1896-1900 in NYC and that the girls are her younger sisters and was a German immigrant".
  - Unidentified Female with 2 Unidentified Young Females (Item 3-215)
    Seated young female on far left wearing patterned dress with belt, scarf at neck, white scalloped collar, hair pulled back, hands folded on lap, standing female center wearing dress with striped pattern, belt, bow at neck, hair pulled back in bow, her rig
  - 2 Unidentified Males and 3 Unidentified Females (Group Portrait) (Item 3-216)
    L-R, top row: male figure standing wearing tall rounded black hat with white collar, light colored open jacket and vest buttoned to top, moustache and sideburns; female standing wearing black dress, tall black hat, holding flowers, earrings; bottom row: s
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-217)
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-218)
    Female figure seated in front of fence, trees and plants in background, wearing striped skirt and white blouse, tall white hat, arms resting on fence, holding umbrella in her right hand.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-219)
  - 2 Unidentified Male Carney Family Members or Friends and 3 Unidentified Female Carney Family Members or Friends (Item 3-220)
    Group of five people, 3 females and 2 males; the ladies are seated, one male is seated, other male is standing to the rear holding an umbrella in his left hand. Full length view, ladies on either end are wearing hats, seated male is wearing striped coat.
  - 3 Unidentified Male Carney Family Members or Friends (Item 3-221)
    Three male figures, one seated, two standing, full length, front view, all three are holding canes, two wearing derbies, one wearing cap, male to the right of seated male has book in right hand.
  - 4 Carney Family Dolls (Item 3-222)
    Four dolls on sofa, three wearing bonnets, long white dresses, full length, front view.
  - 4 Unidentified Carney Family Members or Friends (Item 3-223)
    Three female and one male figure, all seated, in front of ocean backdrop with sailboats; females wearing hats, male holding hat in left hand.
  - 5 Unidentified Young Female Carney Family Members or Friends (Item 3-224)
    Five female figures, 4 seated, one standing, four holding dolls on their laps, all wearing hats, full length view.
  - 8 Unidentified Carney Family Members or Friends (Item 3-225)
    Three females and five male figures, one female and two male are seared, full length, females are wearing hats, male in foreground is holding a straw hat in his right hand, lady in foreground is holding umbrella.
  - L.H. Carney Jr. or Unidentified Male Carney Family Member or Friend, 1888/10/00 (Item 3-226)
    Male figure standing, full length, cane in left hand, front view, chain in vest, bearded, backdrop of a tree, vase on post, wearing glasses.
    Backing states sitters name and date of image.
  - L.H. Carney Jr. or Unidentified Male Carney Family Member or Friend, 1888/10/00 (Item 3-227)
    Male figure standing, full length, left profile, left hand holding a cane, bearded, white collar, standing at backdrop of heavy appearing fence post with vase and tree, wearing glasses.
  - 2 Unidentified Male Figures (Item 3-228)
    Two male figures seated wearing sombreros and holding drinks; Male figure on left wearing bow tie, white shirt, dark pants, legs crossed, holding bottle on knee, moustache; Male figure on right pouring drink from bottle into glass mug, wearing tie, white
  - Cecil H. Cutts and T.W. Idle (Assistant Librarians), 1887/00/00 (Item 3-229)
    Two male figures, one seated, one standing, both with moustaches; backdrop depicts tree and plant.